Guide to the Clyde Brion Davis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Clyde Brion Davis papers
1854-1967
1907-1962
YCAL MSS 255
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.01
(23 boxes)
The Clyde Brion Davis Papers document his work as a journalist and novelist in the United States during the early twentieth century. The Papers contain correspondence and writings as well as personal papers such as business records. The Papers also include correspondence and writings documenting Martha Wirt Davis's writing career.
Davis, Clyde Brion, 1894-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of David B. Davis, 1987.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Clyde Brion Davis (1894-1962)
Clyde Brion Davis, American journalist and novelist, was born in Unadilla, Nebraska, to Charles Nelson and Isabel Brion Davis in 1894. A year later the Davis family moved to Missouri where Davis attended schools in Chillicothe and Kansas City. At fourteen Davis quit school and began a series of odd jobs including printer's apprentice, steam fitter's helper, chimney sweep, and electrician.
In 1916 Davis gained his first experience in journalism working with the Denver Times and Albuquerque Morning Journal. Davis acquired further experience in journalism writing for the army newspaper The Pontanezan Duckboard while serving in the United States Army Intelligence Corps (1917-1919) during World War I. Upon his return to the United States, Davis, with the exception of a few months working for the Burns Detective Agency, spent the years between 1919 and 1937 working for various newspapers, including: Denver Post (1919), Rocky Mountain News (1920-1922), San Francisco Examiner (1921), Seattle Post-Intelligencer (1930), and Buffalo Times (1931-1937).
Davis married Martha Wirt in 1926 and the following year the couple had their only child, David Brion Davis. A native of Denver, Colorado, Martha Wirt (1904?-1952) attended the University of Denver, the Denver Conservatory of Music, and the Art Students League in New York.
Davis wrote a number novels and short stories before the publication of his novel The Anointed in 1937. The Book of the Month Club chose The Anointed as its selection for August 1937 and MGM adapted the novel into the movie "Adventure" (1945) starring Clark Gable and Greer Garson. Following the success of The Anointed, Davis left journalism for a career in creative writing. For the most part he focused on writing novels and short stories, other than a brief period of syndicate work in Europe for PM and Knight newspapers in 1941, two months in Hollywood as a screenwriter, and two years as an associate editor for Rinehart and Company (1943-1945). Davis was awarded a Huntington Hartford fellowship for the years 1956-1957. Over his career Davis wrote over twenty novels including The Great American Novel (1938), The Rebellion of Leo Maguire (1944), and his memoir The Age of Indiscretion (1950).
Martha Wirt Davis was also an artist and writer who published under her own name and the pseudonym Wirt Van Arsdale. She wrote a number of short stories and essays for magazines and in 1951 Doubleday published her mystery novel The Professor Knits a Shroud.
In 1946 Davis and his family moved to Salisbury, Connecticut where Davis was an active citizen (serving as Justice of the Peace between 1947 and 1957) until his death in 1962. Martha Wirt Davis died of a heart attack in 1952.
Scope and Contents
The Clyde Brion Davis Papers document his work as journalist and novelist in the United States and span between the dates 1854 and 1967. The records predominantly date between 1907 and 1967 (also included is a Gleason's Pictorial clipping from 1854). The Papers contain correspondence and writings as well as personal papers such as business records and memorabilia. Davis's drafts and supporting research are included in the Papers along with extensive clippings of his journalism and reviews of his creative writing. The Papers also contain Davis's financial and legal records such as taxes and royalty statements. Correspondence and printed writings documenting Martha Wirt Davis's career are also included in the Papers.
Arrangement
The Clyde Brion Davis Papers is organized into the following four series: Correspondence, Writings, Personal Papers, and Martha Wirt Davis Papers. The Oversize material is listed at the end of the collection.
Buffalo times; American literature -- 20th Century; Fiction -- 20th Century; Film adaptations; Journalists -- United States -- 20th Century; Motion picture plays, American; Novelists, American; Short story; Scrapbooks; Authors; Journalists; Beardshear, Bill; Davis, Clyde Brion, 1894-1962; Davis, Martha Wirt, -1952; Farrar, John Chipman, 1896-1974; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968; Curtis Brown Ltd; Farrar & Rinehart; J.B. Lippincott & Co; Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer; Rosalie Stewart Agency; Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (1992- )
- Correspondence, 1930-1962; Series I; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The series is organized into two subseries: Personal Correspondence and Professional Correspondence. Within each subseries correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. References are provided in cases where Davis's personal and professional correspondence overlap.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains Davis's personal and professional correspondence dating from 1930 to 1962 and documents his personal relationships and career as a journalist and creative writer.
  Davis's fan mail is located with his writings.
  - Personal Correspondence
    - "A" General, 1939-1940, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Angell, Dick, 1946-1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
      Includes typescript draft "Brazilian Report" by Angell
    - "B" General, 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Beardshear, Bill, 1940-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5-13)
    - Black, Wendell, 1945-1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bonner, Willard, 1930-1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes printed version of Bonner's essay "The Ballad of Captain Kidd" dated January 1944
    - Braner, Harry, 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "C" General, 1938, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Casey, Lee, 1940-1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Charles, Fred, 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "D" General, 1938-1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "F" General, 1939-1951 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Farrar, John Chipman, 1936-1947 (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Farrar and Rinehart
    - "G" General, 1939-1945 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Garry, Edward, 1938-1939, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "H" General, 1937-1950 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Hanser, Dick, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - Hippler, Sam, 1938, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Jordan, Collis, 1948 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "L" General, 1945, 1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Lewis, John, 1931, 1946, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Lounsbury, Chas, 1938-1947 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "M" General, 1944, 1946, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1941-1953 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Ortner, H.B., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Parkhill, Forbes, 1940, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - "R" General, 1935, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Raine, Bill, 1939, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Rupp, Mel, 1951, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "S" General, 1939, 1960-1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Smith, Ardis, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Steinbeck, John, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Stewart, George, 1938, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Tipton, Grey, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "V" General, 1944, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "W" General, 1938, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Walsh, Richard, 1935-1938, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - White, E.B., 1947 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - White, W.A., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Wright, Alan, 1939, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Includes 1 black and white photograph of Alan Wright
    - Identified by first name only, 1938-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
    - Unidentified, 1938-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Professional Correspondence
    - "A"-"Z" General, 1938-1957 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - A. and S. Lyons, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Argosy, 1944, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      Includes typescript draft of Davis' article "City Room Liars"
    - Collier's, 1938, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Cosmopolitan, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1937-1948 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Farrar and Rinehart, 1937-1951 (Box 3, Folder 64-67)
      See also: Farrar, John Chipman
    - Harper's, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Holiday, 1954, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Huntington-Hartford Foundation, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - J.B. Lippincott & Co., 1944-1948 (Box 3, Folder 71-73)
    - J.B. Lippincott & Co., 1949-1962 (Box 4, Folder 74-83)
    - Jules C. Goldstone Agency, 10 July 1946 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Kelley-Kramer, 1948, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Little, Brown and Company, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Look Magazine, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures, 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - New Republic, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - The New Yorker, 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Paramount Pictures, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Pathe News, Undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Rosalie Stewart Agency, 1939-1944 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Sloane, William, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Warner Brothers Pictures, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 95)
- Writings, 1909-1960; Series II; 4.8; (13 boxes)
  The series is organized into five subseries: Novels, Short Stories/Essays, Journalism, Other Writings, and Writings of Others. Davis's writings are arranged alphabetically by title and Writings of Others is arranged alphabetically by author (when known).
  The series documents Davis's career as a journalist and creative writer between 1909 and 1962 (with the bulk of material dating from 1930 to 1960). The series contains drafts, background research materials, publicity materials, fan mail, and reviews.
  - Novels
    - 123 Violet
      - Draft, typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - The Age of Indiscretion
      - Publicity material and notes, 1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - Fan mail, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 98-99)
      - Reviews, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 100-101)
    - The Anointed
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1937 (Box 5, Folder 102-103)
      - Publicity, circa 1937 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - Fan mail, 1937-1948 (Box 5, Folder 105-107)
      - Reviews, 1937-1946 (Box 5, Folder 108-109)
      - Scrapbook containing reviews, 1937-1946 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      - Reviews removed from scrapbook, 1937
    - The Arkansas
      - Notes, 1949, undated (Box 7, Folder 111)
        Includes 22 black and white photographs of Arkansas
      - Fan mail, 1939-1942 (Box 7, Folder 112-113)
      - Reviews, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - The Big Pink Kite
      - Contract, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Reviews, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Eyes of Boyhood
      - Notes, circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Fan mail, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - Reviews, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Follow the Leader
      - Notes, circa 1942 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - Fan mail, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - Reviews, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - The Glittering City
      - Draft fragment, undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - The Great American Novel
      - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 124)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1938 (Box 7, Folder 125-127)
      - Third draft fragment, typescript, corrected, circa 1938 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Publicity, 1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Fan mail, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Reviews, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 131-134)
    - Jeremy Bell
      - Publicity, circa 1947 (Box 8, Folder 135)
      - Fan mail, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 136)
      - Reviews, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Nebraska Coast
      - Background materials, 1939, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 138)
        Includes 2 black and white photographs of Nebraska
      - Fan mail, 1938-1941 (Box 8, Folder 139)
      - Scrapbook containing reviews, 1941
      - Reviews removed from scrapbook, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - The Newcomer
      - Reviews, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - North Woods Whammy
      - Reviews, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Northend Wildcats
      - Fan mail, 1938-1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 143)
      - Scrapbook containing reviews, 1939
      - Reviews removed from scrapbook, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Playtime is Over
      - Outline, undated (Box 9, Folder 145)
      - Background materials, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 146-147)
        Includes diary belonging to Alan Wright (who served as inspiration for Playtime is Over ), 1 black and white photograph of unidentified man, and one hand drawn map of unidentified city
      - First draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 9, Folder 148-151)
      - Publicity, 1949, undated (Box 10, Folder 152)
      - Fan mail, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 153)
      - Reviews, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - The Rebellion of Leo McGuire
      - First draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 10, Folder 155-158)
      - Related material, undated (Box 10, Folder 159)
        Includes notes on characters, outline for dramatization, and publicity material.
      - Fan mail, 1943-1951 (Box 10, Folder 160)
      - Reviews, 1944-1951 (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Shadow of a Tiger
      - First draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11, Folder 162-164)
      - Review, undated (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Smoke
      - Draft, typescript, undated (Box 11, Folder 166-167)
    - The Stars Incline
      - Feedback on draft of novel from P.G.W., undated (Box 11, Folder 168)
      - Publicity article by Herbert Gorman "Man with the Seeing Eye", circa 1946 (Box 11, Folder 169)
      - Fan mail, 1945-1950 (Box 11, Folder 170)
      - Reviews, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 171)
    - Sullivan
      - Outline, circa 1940 (Box 11, Folder 172)
      - Fan mail, 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 173)
      - Reviews, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Temper the Wind
      - Publicity, 1948, undated (Box 12, Folder 175)
      - Fan mail, 1947-1948, undated (Box 12, Folder 176)
      - Reviews, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 177)
    - Thudbury: An American Comedy
      - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 178)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 12, Folder 179)
      - Publicity, undated (Box 12, Folder 180)
        Includes 1 black and white photograph of 1905 Mercedes Roadster
      - Fan mail, 1951-1953 (Box 12, Folder 181)
      - Reviews, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - Unholy Uproar
      - Reviews, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 183)
    - Unidentified novel
      - Photographs of Denver, undated (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - Short Stories and Essays
    - ".22 Rifle," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 185)
    - "Albuquerque," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 186)
    - "The American Style: What Delayed It?" draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 187)
    - "Ardis Smith," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 188)
    - "Arkansas," printed version, undated (Box 13, Folder 189)
    - "Back Yard Justice," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 190)
    - "Balkanville," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 191)
    - "Bible Game," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 192)
    - "Bill Bliss," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 193)
    - "Blueprints for the Novel," printed version, 1944 March (Box 13, Folder 194)
    - "Boom Town," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 195)
    - "The Boy and the Bullet," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 196)
    - "Brain Woman," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 197)
    - "Brass Pounders," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 198)
    - "Broken Leg or Baby," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 199)
    - "The Buck Who Got Paid," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - "Bumbershoot Idea," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 201)
    - "Bursting Dam," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 202)
    - "Bushido," drafts, typescript carbon and typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 203)
    - "Calvin Burfield: Potential President," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 204)
    - "Candid Camera," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 205)
    - "Cap Smith," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - "The Chemistry of Cowardice," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - "The Chord of Hope," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 208)
    - "Clarence," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - "Cliff Dwellers," drafts, typescript, 1941, undated (Box 13, Folder 210)
      Includes letter from John Farrar dated 5 August 1941 and notes
    - "Crime Before the Circus," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - "Death of the Brass-Pounder," draft, typescript, 1954, undated (Box 13, Folder 212)
      Includes printed version from The Reporter dated 13 April 1954
    - "Doc Markey," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 213)
    - "The Dragon Knife," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 214)
    - "The Drama of Everyday Life," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 215)
    - "The Dream Ring," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 216)
    - "Dry Cargo," drafts, typescript carbon and typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 217)
    - "Dude," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - "Dummkopf's Martyrdom," draft, typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - "Editing Huck Finn," draft, typescript and related materials, 1935, 1959, undated (Box 14, Folder 220)
      Includes two letters from Harper and Brothers Publishers dated October 15 and October 17, 1935 as well as sequence outline for "The America of Mark Twain" (dated 3 July 1959) and clippings on Mark Twain
    - "Eileen O'Toole and the Seventh Commandment," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 221)
    - "Eric," draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 222)
    - "Fiddle," draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 223)
    - "Forbes Parkhill," draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 224)
    - "Fuzzy Wuzz," draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 225)
    - "Get Off the Hatch," draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 226)
    - "The Governor," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 227)
    - "Heads Up," draft, typescript carbon and typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - "Hit and Run," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 14, Folder 229)
    - "Hometown Revisited," draft, typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 230)
      Includes letter from editor of Tomorrow, Allan Angoff, dated 9 February 1950
    - "Horse Sense"
      - Printed version and reviews, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 231)
      - Fan mail, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 232-237)
    - "I'll Bet on Psychiatry," drafts, typescript, corrected and background materials, 1947, undated (Box 15, Folder 238)
    - "It All Depends," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 239)
    - "Jack Feeney," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 240)
    - "The Jackson Dark Brown," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - "Jasper," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 242)
    - "Jerry," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 243)
    - "Jones," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 244)
    - "Journalism: A Business," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 245)
    - "Judge Claypool's Head," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 246)
    - "Karenville," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 15, Folder 247)
    - "Lathrop," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 248)
    - "A Lesson Learned from Santa Claus," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 249)
    - "A Letter to Mr. Roosevelt," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - "Liars: A Study in Benign Mythomania," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - "Lionel," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - "The Little Guerilla's Ring," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 253)
    - "Little Jules," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 254)
    - "Lucius Edwin," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 255)
    - "M²A For Heroism," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 256)
    - "A Machine Valhalla?" draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 257)
    - "The Magic Algo," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 258)
    - "Man: The Unnecessary ," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 259)
    - "McVeagh," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 260)
    - "Mignon," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 261)
    - "Millicent Dubois Jones," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 262)
    - "Milt," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 263)
    - "Miss Vebelin," draft, typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 264)
    - "The Modest Miser and His Irish Indian," drafts, typescript carbon and typescript, undated (Box 15, Folder 265)
    - "Moses," draft, typescript, notes, and outline, undated (Box 16, Folder 266)
    - "Mr. Bird's Gizzard Stones," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 267)
    - "Mr. Flugel and Pure Science," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 268)
    - "Murders Unsolved," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 269)
    - "My Musical Autobiography," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 270)
    - "Nick," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 271)
    - "The Ninth Notice," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 272)
    - "No Story," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 273)
    - "Noah and the Ark," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 274)
    - "Officers' Women," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 275)
    - "One Ghost Did It," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 276)
    - "The Only Mike," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 277)
    - "Pappy is Fifty," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 278)
    - "The Patricide of Pumpkin, Darling," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 279)
    - "The Perfect Alibi," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 280)
    - "Perpetual Motion," drafts, typescript carbon and typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 281)
    - "Pontanezen," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 282)
    - "Portrait of a Lady," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 283)
    - "Premonition," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 284)
    - "Pretty Bobby Shafto," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 285)
    - "Pulp Paper," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 286)
    - "Purgatory Freight Train," The Frontier, 1932 March (Box 16, Folder 287)
    - "The Queer," draft, typescript, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 288)
    - "Report of Operative 89-B," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 16, Folder 289)
    - "Rocket Rider," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 290)
    - "The Royal Gorge Railroad War," draft, typescript, 1946, undated (Box 16, Folder 291)
    - "Sam Hippler," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 292)
    - "Sangre de Cristo," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 293)
    - "The Schizogenesis of Sadie Fuller," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 294)
    - "The Sea is a Siren," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 295)
    - "The Singing Lizard," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 296)
    - "The Ski and Me," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 297)
    - "Small Town Editor," draft, typescript and printed version, undated (Box 16, Folder 298)
    - "Smoky Hill Romance," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 299)
    - "Something for Mike," draft, typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 300)